Guide to the Roman Gulʹ Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1900-66; Series II; 9.25; (24 boxes)
  - NOVYI ZHURNAL
    - Sobolev, Petr Grigor'evich
      - "Ogurchenyi udar: pamiati G. I. Uspenskogo", 1956 (Box 43, Folder 1077)
    - Solovev, Aleksandr Vasil'evich: "Veroiatnyi avtor 'Slova o polku Igoreve'" (Box 43, Folder 1078)
    - Speranskii, Valentin N.: "Iskrennost' Tolstogo", [1952] (Box 43, Folder 1079)
    - Stankevich, Vladimir Benediktovich: "Iz letnikh razmyshlenii", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1080)
    - Step, Eugene S.: "Perevernutaia karta", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1081-82)
    - Stephen, Fedor Avgustovich: "Pamiati Gustava Gustavovicha Kul'mana", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1083)
    - Stoiunina, M. N.: "Vospominaniia", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1084-85)
    - Stranoliubskii, Petr: "Za predelami uprugosti", 1947 (Box 44, Folder 1086)
    - Sven, Viktor: "Poslednii skif", 1964 (Box 44, Folder 1087)
    - Tabor, Marina / Desmond, Leslie: "The Twilight of Alexey Vanin", 1959 (Box 44, Folder 1088)
    - Taiga, Aleksandr: "Bylina o Borise Pasternake i Nikite Nedobrom", 1959 (Box 44, Folder 1089)
    - Taigin, Nikolai: "Neobyknovennaia istoriia", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1090)
    - Tanutrov, Georgii F.: "Tiflis. Iz knigi Ot Tiflisa do Parizha, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1091)
    - Tauber, Ekaterina
      - "O temakh i obrazakh A. Ladinskogo", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1092)
      - "Pereval", 1963 (Box 44, Folder 1093)
    - Tel'nov, IAkov Arkhipovich: "Antipody. Kapitalizm i sotsializm... ", 1958 (Box 44, Folder 1094)
    - Teplov, Grigorii: "Pamiati Evgeniia Andreevicha, grafa Salias de Turnemir", 1958 (Box 44, Folder 1095)
    - Trubetskoi, Nikolai Sergeevich, kniaz'
      - "Dostoevskii kak khudozhnik", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1096)
      - "Biografiia Dostoevskogo", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1097)
      - "Tvorchestvo Dostoevskogo", n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1098-1102)
    - Ungern-Sternberg, Maria, baroness: "Serenada Braga; rasskaz", [1951] (Box 44, Folder 1103)
    - Unkovskii, Vladimir Nikolaevich: Piatoe koleso: iz zapisok Pegasiia Shapovalenko", [1953] (Box 44, Folder 1104)
    - Usov, Sergei Vasil'evich: "Pokaiannaia ispoved'", 1953 (Box 44, Folder 1105-06)
    - Valentinov, N. (Box 45)
      See: Vol'skii, Nikolai Vladislavovich, Box 46, folder 1140
    - Varetskii, Dm.: "Komandarmy", 1948 (Box 45, Folder 1107)
    - Vaskevich, P. IU
      - "IAponiia ulybaetsia", 1952 (Box 45, Folder 1108)
      - "IAponiia v nastoiashchem... i prognozy... ", 1951 (Box 45, Folder 1109-10)
      - "K voprosu ob iaponskom iskusstve i ego znachenii", 1953 (Box 45, Folder 1111)
      - "Otklik na gogolevskie torzhestva na farme ROVA", 1952 (Box 45, Folder 1112)
      - "Pravdivii golos o Rossii", 1951 (Box 45, Folder 1113)
      - "Ulybka iapontsev", 1951 (Box 45, Folder 1114)
    - Veksler, Aleksandra: "Andrei Belyi" (Box 45, Folder 1115)
    - Velichkovskii, Anatolii Evgen'evich: "Eros", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1116-17)
    - Vel'skaia, M.
      See: Ungern-Sternberg, Maria, baroness, Box 44, folder 1103
    - Vendziagol'skii, K. N.: "Savinkov" (Box 45, Folder 1118-22)
    - Verita, Alësha: "Segodnia veselo zhivetsia, a zavtra budet veselei", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1123)
    - Verkhovenin, L.: "Veshchii son: iz zhizni russkikh emigrantov v Brazilii", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1124)
    - Vikhrovskii, N.
      - "Pustoi razgovor; razskaz", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1125)
      - "Selo Natëchnoe; povest'", n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1126-28)
      - "Son Shurki-ozornoi; roman", n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1129-34)
    - Vishniak, Mark Ven'iaminovich
      - "O materi Marii", n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1135)
      - "O obshchestvennom mnenii v SSSR", n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1136)
      - "'Pobeda Pasternaka'... interesna", 1958 (Box 46, Folder 1137)
    - Vishnitzer, Mark L'vovich
      See: Wischnitzer, Mark, Box 46, folder 1150
    - Volkova, Evgeniia
      - "Lukomor'e", 1963 (Box 46, Folder 1138)
      - "Nevesta", 1953 (Box 46, Folder 1139)
    - Vol'skii, Nikolai Vladislavovich
      - "Besedy s G. V. Plekhanovym", 1954 (Box 46, Folder 1140)
      - "Detstvo i iunost' Lenina", [1953?] (Box 46, Folder 1141)
      - "O predkakh Lenina i ego biografiiakh", [1960?] (Box 46, Folder 1142)
      - "Vstrechi s Andreem Belym", [1956?] (Box 46, Folder 1143-44)
      - "Vydumki o rannei revoliutsionnosti Lenina", [1953?] (Box 46, Folder 1145)
    - Volzhanin-Nizhegorodets, Aledsandr Alekseevich: "Kratkaia programma Russkogo osvoboditel'nogo dvizheniia XX veka", 1962 (Box 47, Folder 1146)
    - Vrangel', Liudmila Sergeevna (Elpat'evskaia): "Provans", [1956] (Box 47, Folder 1147)
    - Vvedenskii: "Chelovek bez imeni", [1953] (Box 47, Folder 1148)
    - Williams, Mrs. Ariadna (Tyrkova): "Bes; glava iz romana'Vasilisa Premudraia'", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1149)
    - Wischnitzer, Mark: "Stranitsy vospominanii. Petersburgskii period", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1150)
    - Zabello, Nikolai Nikolaevich
      - "'Pobeda melodii'; razskaz iz... sbornika" 'Na beregakh Bosfora'", 1925 (Box 47, Folder 1151)
      - "'Podkova'. Iz serii 'Na beregakh Bosfora'", [1925?] (Box 47, Folder 1152)
    - Zaitsev, Boris: "Reka vremen", 1964 (Box 47, Folder 1153)
    - Zakharov, Aleksei Alekseevich
      - "Nachalo Pervoi Mirovoi voiny", [1963?] (Box 47, Folder 1154)
      - "Novoe o Chekhove", [1963?] (Box 47, Folder 1155)
      - "Russko-amerikanskaia tragi-komediia", [1963?] (Box 47, Folder 1156)
      - "Stranstvovanie po Europe", [1963?] (Box 47, Folder 1157)
      - "Vzryvy na ostrove... ", [1963?] (Box 47, Folder 1158)
      - "Zhzn' [!] i tvorchestvo Chekhova", [1963?] (Box 47, Folder 1159)
    - [Zander, Lev Aleksandrovich]: "Obrazy Gretsii" (Box 47, Folder 1160)
    - [Zdorovets, Ivan]: "Tainy serago doma", 1950 (Box 47, Folder 1161-65)
    - Zeeler, Vladimir Feofilovich: "V pol'zu nedostatochnykh studentov", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1166)
    - Zen'kovskii, Vasilii Vasil'evich: "Religioznye temy v tvorchestve B. K. Zaitseva", [1951?] (Box 47, Folder 1167)
    - Zenizov, Vladimir Mikhailovich: "Zapisi... besed s I. A. Buninym", 1934 (Box 47, Folder 1168)
    - Zlobin, Vladimir
      - "Bezvykhodnoe polozhenie; sketch", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1169)
      - "D. S. Merezhkovskii i ego bor'ba s bol'shevikami", 1953 (Box 47, Folder 1170)
      - "'Neistovaia dusha'. Iz knigi o Z. Gippius", 1954 (Box 47, Folder 1171)
      - "'Ognennyi krest'. Glava iz knigi o Z. Gippius", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1172-73)
    - [Zotov], A. V.: "Kompressory s zapada", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1174)
    - Zubarev, Sergei: "Nikolai Vtoroi; istoricheskaia tragediia v trekh chastiakh", n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1175)
    - Zubov, Valentin Platonovich
      - "Predislovie [iz Istorii zhizni Ivana Andreevicha IAkubovskogo]" (Box 47, Folder 1176)
      - "Stranitsy vospominanii, [1960?] (Box 47, Folder 1177)
    - Unidentified authors
      - "Armiia na podnozhnom kormu.. .", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1178)
      - "Chto skryvaet sovetskaia propaganda" (Box 48, Folder 1179)
      - "Drevo na kamne", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1180)
      - "Dvadtsat' pervyi medikosanitarnyi batalion", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1181)
      - "Ekonomicheskie zametki", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1182)
      - "Evgenii Onegin", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1183)
      - "Fedorova... v Europe... ne znaiut", [1933] (Box 48, Folder 1184)
      - "Filosofia elity... vozzreniia Konstantina Leont'eva", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1185)
      - "'Gogol'' i 'Portret'", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1186)
      - "I sobaki gibli za vozhdia", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1187)
      - ISTORIK: "Pis'mo v redaktsiiu", 1960 (Box 48, Folder 1188)
      - ["Iz vostochnoi mudrosti"], n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1189)
      - "Kak bytie opredeliaet soznanie", 1950 (Box 48, Folder 1190)
      - "Kak okhotilis' za liud'mi", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1191)
      - "Krolich'ia shkurka", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1192)
      - "Neprikosnovennost' lichnosti, na slovakh i dele", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1193)
      - ODIN IZ NOVYKH: "Zubry revut", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1194)
      - "Opiat' trevoga", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1195)
      - "Russkoe v evreiskom i evreiskoe v russkom", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1196)
      - S., arkhimandrit: "Tiurma", 1945 (Box 48, Folder 1197)
      - "Shpionazh v pol'zu IAponii", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1198)
      - "Shtrafniki", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1199)
      - "Soldaty i serzhantskii sostav", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1200)
      - "Taktika 'spiashchego' marshala", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1201)
      - "V chulane i na dosprosakh", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1202)
      - "V zhenskom batal'one smerti", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1203)
      - "Vo vlasti dvoinogo zabluzhdeniia", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1204)
      - "Vospominaniia Kievlianina", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1205)
      - "Vse iz-za parshivogo pal'tsa", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1206)
  - OTHER WRITINGS
    - Aleksinskii, Grigorii A.: "Pis'ma k svoim i chuzhim", 1953 (Box 48, Folder 1207)
    - Dobrovol'skaia, Ol'ga Dmitrievna: "Imperator Nikolai Vtoroi i Kerenskii", 1919 (Box 48, Folder 1208)
    - IAtsevich, Aleksei Viktorovich: "O chem umolchal g-n Vishnevskii?"; "Teoriia doktora S. Rossokhi", 1950-[51?] (Box 48, Folder 1209)
    - Koriakov, Mikhail Mikhailovich: "Pochemu ia vozvrashchaius' v SSSR", [1949] (Box 48, Folder 1210)
    - L. L.: "Antiamerikanskoe nastuplenie... Voznesenskogo.. .", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1211)
    - Levitov: "Proekt pravila nosheniia... znaka.. .", [1931] (Box 48, Folder 1212)
    - "Nas vyrastil Stalin.. .", 1948 (Box 48, Folder 1213)
    - "Pokhishchenie nevozvrashchentsa Ivana Tashenkova (... Usmanova)", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1214)
    - "Rapport Kennan.. .", [1952?] (Box 48, Folder 1215)
    - Rudnev, Vladimir Mikhailovich: "Pravda o russkoi tsarskoi sem'e i temnykh silakh", 1919 (Box 48, Folder 1216)
    - Savin, Petr Panteleimonovich: "Vynuzhdenyi otvet S. Riasnianskomu", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1217)
    - Stevens, Leslie Clark: "Russkaia doktrina", [1952?] (Box 48, Folder 1218)
    - Stiranko, M.: "IUdaizm bez prikras", n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1219)
    - Vorontsova - Dashkova, L. N., grafinia; "Chelovek otrekshiisia ot trona" [Zapiski R. B. Gul'ia rasskazov grafini o vel. kn. Mikhaile Aleksandroviche", [1937?] (Box 48, Folder 1220)
    - Unidentified (about Leningrad), 1942, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1220a)
  - POETRY
    - Arbatsky, Yury, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 1221)
    - Askol'dov, V., n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1222)
    - Bakunina, Ekaterina, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 1223)
    - Bal'mont, Konstantin Dmitrievich, 1924 (Box 49, Folder 1224)
    - Berestovskaia, Evgeniia, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1225)
    - Berezov, Rodion Mikhailovich, 1956 (Box 49, Folder 1226)
    - Bobrov, Sergei, 1954 (Box 49, Folder 1227)
    - Bunin, Ivan Alekseevich, 1925-[51?] (Box 49, Folder 1228-31)
    - Bychko, G., n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1232)
    - Choban-Zade, Bekir, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1233)
    - Danilovskii, A., 1953 (Box 49, Folder 1234)
    - Dartatz, O., 1929, 1935 (Box 49, Folder 1235)
    - Dostoevskii, Fedor Fedorovich, 1917-20 (Box 49, Folder 1236)
    - Durakov, Aleksei Petrovich, [1936] (Box 49, Folder 1237)
    - Elachich, Gavriil Aleksandrovich (Box 49, Folder 1238)
    - Elagin, Ivan, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1239)
    - Eremenko, E., 1947-52, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 1240)
    - Evangulov, Georgii, 1934-51 (Box 49, Folder 1241)
    - Fessenko, Tatiana (Sviatenko), 1948 (Box 49, Folder 1242-43)
    - Gippius, Z. N. (Zinaida Nikoaevna), [1900?], 1918 (Box 49, Folder 1244)
    - Gorianskii, Valentin, [1917?] (Box 49, Folder 1245)
    - Griskat, Irina, [1953] (Box 49, Folder 1246)
    - IAblonovskii, Sergei, 1948, 1952 (Box 49, Folder 1247)
    - Ivanov, Georgii Vladimirovich, 1953-[58?] (Box 49, Folder 1248-55)
    - Ivanov, Pavel, 1942-50 (Box 50, Folder 1256)
    - Ivanov, V. I. (Viacheslav Ivanovich), 1915, 1917 (Box 50, Folder 1257)
    - Koniskii, P., [1951?] (Box 50, Folder 1258)
    - Korvin-Piotrovskii, Vladimir L'vovich, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1259-60)
    - Lebedev, Sergei, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 1261)
    - Makovskii, Sergei Konstantinovich, 1946-60, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1262)
    - Mikulovskii, Iosip Stepanovich, 1943 (Box 50, Folder 1263)
    - Morshen, Nikolai, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1264)
    - Odarchenko, IUrii, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1265)
    - Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimirovna, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 1266)
    - Osherova, Polina, [1961?] (Box 50, Folder 1267)
    - Pletnev, R. (Rastislav), [1955] (Box 50, Folder 1268)
    - Pokhlebina, Nina, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1269)
    - Pugachov, Vsevolod, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1270)
    - Savinkov, B. V. (Boris Viktorovich), n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1271)
    - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 1272)
    - Smolenskii, Vladimir, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1273)
    - Stankevich, Vladimir Benediktovich, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1274)
    - Sumnyi, M., n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1275)
    - TSvetaeva, Marina, 1936 (Box 50, Folder 1276)
    - Trubetskoi, IUrii, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1277)
    - Veitsman, Filipp, [1955] (Box 50, Folder 1278)
    - Vodnevskii, Nikolai, 1954 (Box 50, Folder 1279)
    - Volin, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1280)
    - Zabello, Nikolai Nikolaevich, 1955-56 (Box 50, Folder 1281)
    - Zaslawski, S., 1936-52 (Box 50, Folder 1282)
    - Zlobin, Vladimir, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1283-84)
    - Unidentified
      - E. L., n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1285)
      - "Ne u nas na Maiami", n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1286)
      - "O chem ne pisali v gazetakh", n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1287)
      - "Tri tankista.. .", n.d. (Box 50, Folder 1288)
- Subject Files, 1938-64; Series III; 6; (21 boxes)
  Series III, Subject Files, is found in Boxes 51-71. The material is divided into three subseries: Narodnaia Pravda - Subcribers Correspondence (Boxes 51-53), alphabetically arranged. Political Organizations (Boxes 54-60) - further subdivided into five subsections (Liga bor'by za narodnuiu svobodu; Natsional'no - trudovoi souiz; Rossiiskoe narodnoe dvizhenie; Soiuz bor'by za osvobozhdenie narodov Rossii; Soviet osvobozhdeniia narodov Rosii), and Radio Broadcasting and Scripts, also divided into two subsections (Voice of America; Radio Liberty). The last two sections are arranged by subject. Folders 1811-12 represent an addition to the Roman Gul' Papers.
  - NARODNAIA PRAVDA - SUBSCRIBERS' CORRESPONDENCE
    - "A" general, 1949-52 (Box 51, Folder 1289-91)
    - "B" general, 1948-52 (Box 51, Folder 1292-96)
    - "C" general, 1949-53, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1297-98)
    - "D" general, 1948-52 (Box 51, Folder 1299-1300)
    - "E" general, 1951-52 (Box 51, Folder 1301)
    - "F" general, 1949-52 (Box 51, Folder 1301-02)
    - "G" general, 1949-52 (Box 51, Folder 1303-06)
    - "H" general, 1950-52, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1307-08)
    - "I" general, 1949-52, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1308-10)
    - "J" general, 1950-51 (Box 51, Folder 1311)
    - "K", general (Box 51, Folder 1311-18)
    - "L" general, 1950-52, n.d. (Box 51, Folder 1319-21)
    - "M" general, 1948-52 (Box 52, Folder 1322-27)
    - "N" general, 1949-52, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1327-29)
    - "O" general, 1948-52 (Box 52, Folder 1329-30)
    - "P" general, 1949-52 (Box 52, Folder 1330-34)
    - "R" general, 1950-52 (Box 52, Folder 1335-37)
    - "S" general, 1948-52, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1338-46)
    - "T" general, 1948-52, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1347-48)
    - "U" general, 1950-52 (Box 52, Folder 1348-49)
    - "V" general, 1950-52 (Box 52, Folder 1349-52)
    - "W" general, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 1352)
    - "Y" general, 1950 (Box 52, Folder 1352)
    - "Z" general, 1949-52 (Box 52, Folder 1352-53)
    - Unidentified, 1949-52 (Box 52, Folder 1354)
    - Financial papers & others, 1948-53, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1355-57)
  - POLITICAL ORGANIZATIONS
    - Liga bor'by za narodnuiu svododu
      - Protokoly soveta Ligy, 1948-51 (Box 54, Folder 1358-97)
      - Protokoly biura Ligy, 1949-51 (Box 55, Folder 1398-1431)
      - Miscellany, 1949-51, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1432-69)
    - Natsional'no-trudovoi soiuz
      - Letters, 1950-57, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1470)
      - Miscellany, [1951]-56, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1471)
      - By and about, 1938-52, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1472-88)
    - Rossiiskoe narodnoe dvizhenie
      - Documents, 1950-52 (Box 58, Folder 1489)
      - Financial papers, 1951-52 (Box 58, Folder 1490)
      - Membership, 1951 (Box 58, Folder 1491)
      - Letters: outgoing A-Z, 1948-52, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1492-95)
      - Letters: incoming A-V, 1948-53, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1496-97)
      - Miscellany, 1948-53, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1498-1502)
      - "Cases", 1951-52, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1503-12)
    - Soiuz bor'by za osvobozhdenie narodov Rossii
      - TSentral'nyi komitet
        - Letters, 1949-52, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1513)
        - Miscellany, 1948-51, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1514)
      - Severno-amerikanskii otdel, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 1515)
    - Soviet osvobozhdeniia narodov Rossii (SONR)
      - Biuro po sozyvu SONR
        - Letters and documents, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 1516)
      - O sozdanii SONR
        - Soveshchanie liderov trekh, 1951, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1517)
        - Soveshchenie liderov chetyrekh, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 1518)
        - Soveshchenie liderov piati, 1951 (Box 60, Folder 1519)
          - Gul' R. B.: "O konferentsii piati", [1951] (Box 60, Folder 1520)
          - Kurganov, I. A.: "Vtoromu plenumu piati", [1951] (Box 60, Folder 1521)
  - RADIO BROADCASTING AND SCRIPTS
    - Miscellaneous material, [195-?]-61 (Box 61, Folder 1522-35)
    - Voice of America
      - Dated scripts, 1949-51 (Box 62, Folder 1536-51)
      - "Kul'turnaia rabota russkoi emigratsii", [195-?] (Box 63, Folder 1552-61)
      - Beseda s Gulem, [195-?] (Box 63, Folder 1562)
    - Radio Liberty (Munich, Germany)
      - "Nashe demokraticheskoe nasledstvo", 1955, [195-?] (Box 64-65, Folder 1563-1633)
      - "Rosiia na zapade", 1954-[55] (Box 66-67, Folder 1634-1720)
      - "Sovremennaia russkaia literatura", [195-?] (Box 68, Folder 1721-37)
      - "Zaria svobody", [195-?] (Box 69, Folder 1738-59)
      - "Zarubezhnaia russkaia literatura", 1955, [195-?] (Box 70, Folder 1760-99)
      - "O svobode naroda", [195-?] (Box 71, Folder 1800)
      - "Oktiabr'skaia kontr-revolutsiia", [195-?] (Box 71, Folder 1801-05)
      - "Pis'ma na rodinu", [195-?] (Box 71, Folder 1806)
      - "Problemy ideologii", 1964 (Box 71, Folder 1807-08)
      - "Russkaia svobodnaia mysl'", [196-?] (Box 71, Folder 1809)
      - "Zapretnye stranitsy", 1954 (Box 71, Folder 1810)
    - Addition
      - Bibliograficheskii biulleten' radiostantsii "Svoboda", 1960-62 (Box 71, Folder 1811)
      - Radio Free Europe. Research and Evaluation Department, 1962 (Box 71, Folder 1812)
- Printed Works, 1879-1966; Series IV; 2.25; (10 boxes)
  Series IV, Printed Works, contains two boxes of alphabetically arranged Serials (Boxes 77-78), and three boxes of Clippings (Boxes 79-81), arranged by subject.
  Separated Materials
  Books and pamphlets, formerly housed in boxes 72-76, and the bulk of the serials formerly housed in boxes 77-78, have been removed for individual cataloging.
  - BOOKS AND PAMPHLETS
    Books and pamphlets, formerly housed in boxes 72-76, have been removed and cataloged individually in Orbis, the Yale University Library catalog.
  - SERIALS
    - [ Contacts littéraires et sociaux: revue de critique littéraire ], [195-?] (Box 78, Folder 1874)
    - [ Rodnye perezvony ], 1960-61 (Box 78, Folder 1891)
    - Vil'ne slovo demokrata, 1949-52 (Box 78, Folder 1901)
    - Za svododu: organ R.N.D.
      See: Oversize, Box 88 folder 2123
  - CLIPPINGS
    - Various subjects, [1934]-54, n.d. (Box 79, Folder 1903-11)
    - Various subjects, 1955-66, n.d. (Box 80, Folder 1912-21)
    - Biographies, necrologies A-V, [1936]-66, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1922-25)
    - Debate: Gul'-Kuskova, 1950 (Box 81, Folder 1926)
    - Gul', R. B. (by, about), 1933-[65], n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1927)
    - Pasternak, Boris and his "Doktor Zhivago", 1958-64, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1928-29)
    - "Narodnaia pravda" (about), 1948-50 (Box 81, Folder 1930)
    - "Novyi zhurnal" (reviews), 1952-[64] (Box 81, Folder 1931)
    - [Vlasovtsy], 1945, n.d. (Box 81, Folder 1932)
    - Various subjects in various languages, 1939-66 (Box 81, Folder 1933-34)
- Photographs, 1881-1966; Series V; 0.5; (3 boxes)
  Series V, Photographs, is divided into three subseries: People (Boxes 82-84), Places and Others, and Album (Box 84). Subseries People is further subdived into three sections: Individuals, Groups. and Portraits. The material is arranged alphabetically by subject; under Gul' the arrangement is chronological.
  - PEOPLE
    - Individuals
      - Bandera, Stepan A., [194-?] (Box 82, Folder 1935)
      - Durakov, Aleksei Petrovich, 1936, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1936-37)
      - Evtushenko, Evgenii Aleksandrovich, 1963 (Box 82, Folder 1938)
      - Fedin, Konstantin, 1928-32, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1939-42)
      - Gippius, Z. N. (Zinaida Nikolaevna), [1907?] (Box 82, Folder 1943)
      - Gul', Roman Borisovich, 1940, 1962 (Box 82, Folder 1944-45)
      - Hofmann, Modeste, 1957, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1946)
      - Ivanov, Georgii Vladimirovich, 1955, 1958, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1947)
      - Ivanovskii, A., [1950] (Box 82, Folder 1948)
      - Ivnev, Riurik, [1926] (Box 82, Folder 1949)
      - Khadzhiev, Razak, 1917-20, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1950)
      - Korvin-Piotrovskii, Vladimir L'vovich, 1946 (Box 82, Folder 1951)
      - Kruglikov, Samuil, 1949 (Box 82, Folder 1952)
      - Makovskii, Sergei Konstantinovich, 1953 (Box 82, Folder 1953)
      - Meisner, Ivan Ivanovich, [19--?] (Box 82, Folder 1954)
      - Merezhkovskii, Dmitrii Sergeevich, [1907?] (Box 82, Folder 1955)
      - Mirchuk, Petro, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1956)
      - Mishatkin, Nikolai Fedorovich, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1957)
      - Nikitin, Nikolai, 1928 (Box 82, Folder 1958)
      - Nicolaevsky, Boris I., [1951] (Box 82, Folder 1959)
      - Paustovskii, Konstantin, 1963 (Box 82, Folder 1960)
      - Petreskii, Ivan Vasil'evich, 1941 (Box 82, Folder 1961)
      - Pomerantsev, Kirill Dmitrievich, 1958 (Box 82, Folder 1962)
      - Saninian, Suren, [1960] (Box 82, Folder 1963)
      - Semenov-Tian-Shanskii, Valerii Petrovich, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 1964)
      - Smolenskii, Vladimir, 1949-61 (Box 82, Folder 1965-66)
      - Turgenev, Ivan Sergeevich, [1881?] (Box 82, Folder 1967)
      - Trubetskoi, IUrii, [1954] (Box 82, Folder 1968)
      - Turoverov, Nikolai Nikolaevich, [1960?], 1966 (Box 82, Folder 1969-70)
      - Vendziagol'skii, Karol' Mikhailovich, [1959] (Box 82, Folder 1971)
      - Vitlin, Iosif, [1960] (Box 82, Folder 1972)
      - Vodov, Sergei Akimovich, 1962 (Box 82, Folder 1973)
      - Zaitsev, Boris, 1963 (Box 82, Folder 1974)
      - Zakharov, Aleksei Alekseevich, [196-?] (Box 82, Folder 1975)
      - Zamiatin, Evgenii Ivanovich, 1931 (Box 82, Folder 1976)
      - Zaretskii, Nikolai Vasilevich, [1927?] (Box 82, Folder 1977)
      - Zavalishin, Viacheslav, [1960] (Box 82, Folder 1978)
      - Zenzinov, Vladimir Mikhailovich, [1951] (Box 82, Folder 1979)
    - Groups
      - Adamovich, Georgii Viktorovich, and Odoevtseva, Irina Vladimirovna, 1963 (Box 83, Folder 1980)
      - Annenkov, IUrii Pavlovich, and
        - [his wife?], 1963 (Box 83, Folder 1981)
        - Trotsky, Leon, [192-?] (Box 83, Folder 1982)
        - TSurikov, A. N., 1961 (Box 83, Folder 1983)
      - Bunin, Ivan Alekseevich, and Andrew, Shaliapin, Teleshov, Chirikov, Skitalets, Gorky (Box 83, Folder 1984)
      - Bystrov, Ivan, and his family and friend, 1962 (Box 83, Folder 1985)
      - Dostoevskaia, Ekaterina Petrovna, and Fal'ts-Fein, Nina Petrovna, [1948?] (Box 83, Folder 1986)
      - Evtushenko, Evgenii Aleksandrovich, and unidentified persons, 1963 (Box 83, Folder 1987)
      - Fedin, Konstantin; Nikitin, Nikolai and Arkus, A. M., 1928 (Box 83, Folder 1988)
      - Fessenko, Tatiana (Sviatenko) and Fessenko, Andrei Vladimirovich, 1949 (Box 83, Folder 1989)
      - Gul', Roman Borisovich and
        - Orlov, Nikolai Afan, [1925] (Box 83, Folder 1990)